Inventory of the Academy For Educational Development Records, 1956-1986
Hoover Institution Archives
- States. (Box No. 61-72.)
  - Colorado
    - Terman, Frederick E., "Excellence in Science and Engineering in Colorado Universities." Colorado Commission on Higher Education. 1967, 40 (Box 62.)
  - Connecticut
    - "Teacher Education: An Urgent Matter." Commission for Higher Education, State of Connecticut. 1966, 18
  - District of Columbia
    - "A Proposal for the Consortium of Universities of the Washington Metropolitan Area," 1968, 54
  - Florida
    - "A Call to Action." Joint Legislative and Executive Commission on Postsecondary Education, State of Florida. 1979, 651
  - Hawaii
    - "A Study of the Feasibility of Developing a New Institution." Hawaii Pacific College and Hawaii Loa College. 1977, 326
  - Illinois
    - "A Survey of Faculty Personnel Practices at 32 Urban Community Colleges." Board of Trustees, City Colleges of Chicago. 1976, 264
    - "Report on Teacher Absenteeism in the Public Schools of Illinois." State Board of Education, Illinois Office of Education. 1977, 323 (Box 63.)
  - Indiana
    - "Budget Planning in Indiana." Commission for Higher Education, State of Indiana. n.d., 192
    - Eurich, Alvin C., A Commentary on Medical Education in Indiana, 1965, 12
    - "Report on Activities of Finance Study." Commission for Higher Education, State of Indiana. 1975, 192
    - Planning for Progress through Higher Education. Temporary Committee on Higher Education in North Central Indiana. 1964, 2
  - Kansas
    - Kansas Plans for the Next Generation. Board of Regents, State of Kansas. 1962, 1
  - Maine
    - The First Business of Our Times. Advisory Commission for the Higher Education Study, State of Maine. 1966, 13
  - Massachusetts
    - Terman, Frederick E., Aid to Private Higher Education in Massachusetts: Why? How? Massachusetts Advisory Council on Education. n.d., 152
    - "Higher Education in Massachusetts: A New Look at Some Major Policy Issues." Massachusetts Advisory Council on Education. 1973, 152 (Box 64.)
    - Higher Education in Massachusetts: A New Look at Some\ Major Policy Issues: Summary of the Report. Massachusetts Advisory Council on Education. 1973, 152
  - Mississippi
    - "An Analysis of the Cost to Students Attending Mississippi's Public Universities." Commission of Budget and Accounting, Mississippi Legislature. 1979, 480.l
    - "An Assessment of the State Data Base for Higher Education." Mississippi Commission of Budget and Accounting. 1978, 480.2
    - "Public Senior Institutions of Higher Learning, State of Mississippi: Comparative Analysis of Degree Program Costs." Mississippi Commission of Budget and Accounting. 1979, 480.4
    - "Public Senior Institutions of Higher Learning, State of Mississippi: Energy Cost, Consumption, and Conservation Practices." Mississippi Commission of Budget and Accounting. 1979, 480.5
    - "Public Senior Institutions of Higher Learning, State of Mississippi: Equipment Management." Mississippi Commission of Budget and Accounting. 1979, 480.6 (Box 65.)
    - Millett, John D., "Essentials of Management Information for Colleges and Universities," n.d., 480.14
    - "Public Senior Institutions of Higher Learning, State of Mississippi: Faculty Productivity and Administrative Practices." Mississippi Commission of Budget and Accounting. 1979, 480.8
    - "Governance of Public Higher Education in Mississippi." Mississippi Commission of Budget and Accounting. 1979, 480.7
    - "An Analysis of Compensation of Employees at Mississippi's Public Universities." Mississippi Commission of Budget and Accounting. 1979, 480
    - "Pathways to Accountability and Excellence: A Final Report on the Status and Future of Public Higher Education in Mississippi." Mississippi Commission of Budget and Accounting. 1979, 480.16
    - "Physical Facilities and Conditions at Eight University Campuses Operated by the Board of Trustees, Institutions of Higher Learning, State of Mississippi: An Evaluative Report on Size, Use, Condition and the Physical Development Process." 1979, 480.10 (Box 66.)
    - "Program Review: A Structure for Mississippi's Public Universities." Mississippi Commission of Budget and Accounting. 1979, 480.12
    - "Projections of Enrollments for Public Senior Institutions in Mississippi." Mississippi Commission of Budget and Accounting. 1978, 480.11
    - "A Report on the Mississippi Junior College System." Mississippi Commission of Budget and Accounting. 1979, 480.9
    - "Governance of Public Higher Education in Mississippi." Mississippi Commission of Budget and Accounting. 1979, 480
    - "Competency Testing and Basic Skills/Developmental Studies Programs at Postsecondary Institutions." State of Mississippi. 1979, 480.17
    - "Analysis and Recommendations on the Funding Formula of Mississippi's Senior Public Institutions." State of Mississippi. 1979, 480.15 (Box 67.)
    - "Competency Testing and Basic Skills/Developmental Studies Programs at Postsecondary Institutions." State of Mississippi. 1979 State of Mississippi: Report on University of Mississippi Medical Center." Mississippi Commission of Budget and Accounting. 1979, 480.3
    - "Public Senior Institutions of Higher Learning, State of Mississippi: Report on University of Mississippi Medical Center." Mississippi Commission of Budget and Accounting. 1979, 480.l3
  - Missouri
    - Looking Ahead to Better Education in Missouri: A Report on Organization, Structure, and Financing of Schools and Junior Colleges. Missouri Governor's Conference on Education. 1966, 15
    - "Graduate Education in the St. Louis, Missouri Area." Higher Education Coordinating Council of Metropolitan St. Louis. 1972, 132
  - New Hampshire
    - "A Report to the New Hampshire Postsecondary Education Commission," 1974, 224
  - New Jersey (Box 68.)
    - "Background for a Master Plan in the State of New Jersey." Department of Higher Education, State of New Jersey. 1971, 98
  - New York
    - Spierer, Howard, "The Brooklyn Institutional Council: A Report of Staff Activities, September 1972-August 1973," 1973, 110.2
    - Kinder, William A., "City College Advisory Workshop, 1973-1974." Office of Educational Evaluation, Board of Education of the City of New York. 1974, 206
    - "Implementing the Merger: PIB-NYU/SES." Polytechnic Institute of New York. 1973, 158.5
    - Wells, Herman B., The Legislature and Higher Education in New York State: A Report by the Legislature's Consultant on Higher Education, 1964, 3
    - "Classroom Manuals for Student Service Personnel of the New York City School System." Security Training Program, New York City Board of Education. 1972, 141 (Box 69.)
    - "Agenda for Action: A Report of the Guidance Advisory Council to the Board of Education of the City of New York," 1972, 114
    - "A Safer Environment for Learning." Panel on School Security Program, New York City Board of Education. 1972, 135.A
    - "The Need for Immediate Action: Safety Personnel and Practices for the New York City Public Schools." Panel on School Security Program, New York City Board of Education. 1972, 135.B
    - "Supplementary Materials Concerning School Security Personnel in the NYC Public Schools." New York City Board of Education, and The Mayor's Criminal Justice Coordinating Council. 1972, 135.C
    - Rosenthal, Neal H., "College Trained Manpower in New York State, 1965-1975: An Analysis of Supply and Demand in Selected Occupations," 1968, 55
    - "Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn: Organizational Structure of Executive Staff," 1973, 158.4
    - Brickell, Henry M., and Carol B. Aslanian, "Needed in New York State: Career Education." New York State Advisory Council on Vocational Education. 1978, P-437
    - "Evaluation of 1972 Training Program for School Safety Personnel," 1972, 141 (Box 70.)
  - Ohio
    - Toward an Effective Utilization of Independent Colleges and Universities by the State of Ohio. Association of Independent Colleges and Universities of Ohio. 1971, 91.2
    - Abrahams, Louise, and Leigh Schweppe, "A Limited Study of the Status of State Support of Private Higher Education, 1970," 1970, 91.1
    - Inter-University Council of Ohio, "Advancing and Preserving Man's Unconquerable Mind." 1978, 268
    - Provisional Master Plan for Public Higher Education in Ohio. Ohio Board of Regents. 1965, 7
    - "Meeting Ohio's Needs for MDs through 1980 and Beyond." Ohio Board of Regents. 1970, 95
    - "A Strategic Approach to the Maintenance of Institutional Financial Stability and Flexibility in the Face of Enrollment Instability or Decline." Ohio Board of Regents. 1979, 457
    - "Institutional and State Level Program Review: Objectives and Process." Ohio Board of Regents. 1979, 457 (Box 71.)
    - "Developing a Process Model for Institutional and State-Level Review and Evaluation of Academic Programs." Ohio Board of Regents. 1979, 457
    - Policy Studies in Education, "Analysis of Student Learning in the Intensified Career Exploration Program: Final Report for the Second Year of VEA Part D Funding." Ohio Career Development Program. 1978, P-390
  - Oregon
    - "Study of Catholic Education in the Archdiocese of Portland in Oregon." 1969, 48.5
  - Pennsylvania
    - "Elements of a Master Plan for Higher Education in Pennsylvania." State Board of Education, Commonwealth of Pennsylvania. 1965, 8
  - Rhode Island
    - Policy Studies in Education, "An Assessment of the Need for Career Education in Rhode Island." Bureau of Vocational-Technical Education, Rhode Island Department of Education. 1979, P-444
  - South Dakota
    - "Meeting the Post-Secondary Education Needs of South Dakota." Regents of Education, State of South Dakota. 1974, 194
  - Texas (Box 72.)
    - "Report to the Board of Regents, the University of Texas System." 1978, 479
  - Washington
    - "Financing Post-Secondary Education in Washington." Council on Higher Education, State of Washington. 1972, 121.1
  - West Virginia
    - "Support, Performance and Protection of Higher Education in West Virginia." Joint Committee on Government and Finance, and Joint Subcommittee on Higher Education, West Virginia Legislature. 1979, 536
    - Utilizing West Virginia's Independent Colleges More Effectively. West Virginia Association of Private Colleges. 1973, 133
    - "A Report to the West Virginia Board of Regents." 1974, 225
- United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization. (Box No. 72-73.)
  - Gross, Ronald, and Judith Murphy, The United States and UNESCO: Challenges for the Future. Special National Conference, United States National Commission for UNESCO. 1966, 20 (Box 72.)
  - Business and Education for World Affairs. Business Task Force, International Education Year Committee, U.S. National Commission for UNESCO. 1971, 82
  - U.S. National Commission for UNESCO, Memo. Special Issue, International Education Year. 1970, 82 (Box 73.)
  - Sullivan, George, "Report on an International Symposium on the Promotion of the Reading Habit." U.S. National Commission for UNESCO. 1976, 258
  - Sullivan, George, A Reason to Read: A Report on an International Symposium on the Promotion of the Reading Habit. U.S. National Commission for UNESCO. 1976, 258
  - "Education in the Seventies: The Essential Revolution." International Education Year Project, U.S. National Commission for UNESCO. 1970, 82
- Planning in Higher Education. (Box No. 73-75)
  - "Program of Continuing Education and Planning Assistance in Change Management: A Report on Experience, January 1, 1976-June 30, 1977." W. K. Kellogg Foundation. 1977, 268 (Box 73.)
  - "Report on Program of Continuing Education and Planning Assistance in Change Management." W. K. Kellogg Foundation. 1977, 268
  - Orser, G. Robert, and Judith Alexander, "Model Schools Advisory Committee Handbook." Community Development Administration, Newark, New Jersey. 1971, E-T.1
  - "Report to the W. K. Kellogg Foundation: Year Ending December 31, 1978," 1978, 268
  - "Higher Education Planning System," 1978, 268 (Box 74.)
  - Millett, John D., "Concept of the University: Operations, Management, Governance, Organization, Planning: A Guide to Academic Management," 1978, 268
  - Nelson, Lester W., "Long-Range Educational Planning for Inner City Areas." Fund for the Advancement of Education. 1968, 49
  - Millett, John D., Challenges in Statewide Planning for\ the l980s. AED Occasional Paper #9. n.d., -
  - The Idea Handbook for Colleges and Universities. 1979, 505
  - John D. Millett. AED Occasional Paper #10. 1979, -
  - Clark Kerr Honored by the Academy. AED Occasional Paper #8. 1978, -
  - AED Papers #l-6. 1965-1973, - (Box 75.)
  - AED Brochures. 1962-1969, -
  - AED Brochures. 1970-1972, -
  - AED Brochures. 1973-1976, -
  - AED Brochure. 1977, -
- Miscellaneous. (Box No. 75)
  - Florio, Carol, Collegiate Programs for Older Adults: A Summary Report on a 1976 Survey. AED Paper #7. 1978, 196.3 (Box 75.)
  - Miscellaneous reports. 1973, 152.2/170/174/182.1/187
  - The Voluntary Sector in Brief. Ford Foundation. 1979, 518
  - Educational Facilities Laboratories, Campus in Transition, 1975, -
- Additional incremental materials (76-168)
  Material has not yet been described.
- Preliminary Inventory to additional incremental materials in boxes 169-460 (169-460)
  Container List
  Downloadable PDF preliminary inventory of the Academy For Educational Development incremental materials